<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ABG Assistant</string>
    <string name="textview">\n \t Suggested results are not a substitute for clinical judgement. All calculations must be confirmed before use.
        The authors make no claims of the accuracy of the information contained herein.
        Neither author of application nor any other party involved in the preparation of publication shall be liable for any special,
        consequential, or exemplary damages resulting in whole or part from any user`s use of or reliance upon this material.
         \n \t Remember that results given by this application are based only on laboratory results.
     This approach has many limitations, eg: reference values are characteristic for specific groups and laboratories, all ABG compensation equations are being questioned, and so on.
    \n \t You should always take into account medical history and patients state.
        \n \t To compare results derived from all of the combinations, you have to enter all required data.
    If you do not enter "albumin" value, you will not be able to get results from the Boston approach with corrected AG nor the Copenhagen approach with corrected AG.


    </string>



    <string name="informations">\n \t Whereas the presence of a high anion gap educes the consideration of a differential
diagnosis by reﬂex in daily clinical practice, a low anion gap often does not elicit the
same warning to clinicians and hence often remains either undiscovered or neglected.
Furthermore, the classical differential diagnosis of a low anion gap has changed since the
ion-selective electrode has been introduced. A low anion gap has two utilities. First, it
can be an early and sometimes only sign of an underlying disease process such as
paraproteinaemia. Second, a low anion gap can mask an underlying high anion gap
acidosis and potentially delay intervention. While an increase in the anion gap is almost
always caused by retained unmeasured anions, a decrease in the anion gap can be
generated by multiple mechanisms.
        \n \t  Acute dilution of the extracellular ﬂuid with either administered or retained
hypotonic ﬂuid will theoretically dilute essentially all ions causing a fall in the anion gap.
However, this type of dilution usually results only in reductions of the anion gap of 1
or 2 mEql/l which will hardly move it out of the laboratory normal range. Severe
hypernatraemia can be underestimated by ﬂame photometry owing to the non-linear
nature of this assay. Because the measurement of plasma chloride and bicarbonate
remains accurate even at increased concentrations, the net result will be a spuriously
low anion gap.
The use of sodium-selective electrodes with a larger dynamic range
negates this artifact from instrument non-linearity. Large non-aqueous volumes in the
plasma, such as hypertriglyceridaemia or dysproteinaemia
, can lead to an
underestimation of serum sodium—especially with ﬂame photometric instruments.
However, sodium-selective electrodes are not spared even though the sodium activity
registered by the sodium electrode is oblivious to the non-aqueous volume. This is
explained in Figure 1. Automatic aspirators and dilutors prepare the samples and, in
situations with excessive non-aqueous volume in plasma, a smaller than expected
plasma volume may be aspirated leading to an underestimation of plasma sodium
during the back-calculation (Figure 1). In the absence of concurrent errors in Cl and HCO3
measurements, a low anion gap ensues. In macroglobulinaemia, the error in
sodium measurement is proportionate to the level of hyperviscosity and can be as
high as 40 mEql/l.
    </string>

</resources>
